<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>post on Parth Paradkar</title>
    <link>https://thescriptninja.github.io/tags/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in post on Parth Paradkar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 18:03:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thescriptninja.github.io/tags/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Content Review 2020</title>
      <link>https://thescriptninja.github.io/posts/content-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 18:03:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thescriptninja.github.io/posts/content-review/</guid>
      <description>In 2020, the amount of time I spent on the internet was probably the highest I have in any previous year and I have consumed a near-unhealthy amount of digital content while being at home for long periods. I thought it would be nice to look back. This is inspired by a recent blogpost by @xypnox.
Literature I read regularly before joining college, but because of involvements on campus and other things to explore, I didn’t read as much as I used to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding correlation between data features</title>
      <link>https://thescriptninja.github.io/posts/understanding-correlation-between-data-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 01:23:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thescriptninja.github.io/posts/understanding-correlation-between-data-features/</guid>
      <description>Understanding correlation One of the main questions I faced while exploring data was that how can I measure the strength of the relationship between two features of the data.
For example, how is the price of a car related with its mileage? How do we quantify their interdependence? How strong is the relationship?
I attempt to explore this mathematically in this notebook.
# Importing the required libraries import pandas as pd import seaborn as sns We shall consider a dataset that gives the specifications of cars and their prices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://thescriptninja.github.io/posts/first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 09:20:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thescriptninja.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid>
      <description>After a LOT of Google searches, deleted repositories and headaches born out of frustration, this blog is finally and thankfully up and running. Who was the guy who said Jekyll was easy?
Now that a blog has been born, so has the responsibility of posting regularly. So let&amp;rsquo;s see how this works out! But for now, Adios!
BTW here is the most useful link I found to create this blog</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
